<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Install on Transcrobes</title>
    <link>/page/software/learn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Install on Transcrobes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/page/software/learn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Content Stats</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/content-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/content-stats/</guid>
      <description>In various places in the application that analyse and enrich content you can find little coloured boxes that appear, like you can see on the Content list page
Or on Brocrobes, that appears when you Transcrobe a webpage
Colours The system colour-codes the expected difficulty level, depending on the percentage of known words and the sentence length. We&amp;rsquo;re working on more advanced and even more personalised options at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Stats</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/stats/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the current state of your knowledge and how that has evolved over time is a very effective way for many learners to make the most of their learning time and (mental) effort. Transcrobes will eventually provide a very rich interface for analysing and understanding many aspects of learning, including what the most effective activities are for each individual learner.
While we are just at the beginning, Transcrobes aims to be a quantified self project for language learning - helping you to deeply understand how you - and that means YOU and not some random, Ivory Tower abstraction - learn best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! Transcrobes is an open ecosystem for learning languages, with actual learners at the centre of all research, development and services.
It is open source, open research and open education.
Sign up for free to be a part of Transcrobes today
What can it do? Transcrobes provides deeply individualised comprehension and learning aids, to turn any authentic text into an optimised tool for language learning. Get help only with the stuff you need help for, with automatic glosses for unknown words, and on-demand definitions, translations, similar sentences, synonyms, and direct integration with active learning tools like spaced repetition, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boocrobes</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/boocrobes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/boocrobes/</guid>
      <description>Boocrobes Boocrobes allows you to read ebooks in the EPUB format using personalised comprehension aids, including when you are offline. The module is a (very slightly) adapted version of the amazing open source javascript &amp;ldquo;Readium V2&amp;rdquo; R2D2BC reader developed by Aferdita Muriqi, with the addition of the special Transcrobes sauce that connects you to the model the system has of your language knowledge. The integration is not yet perfect, so you may need to refresh the page occasionally if the formatting does something strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brocrobes</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/brocrobes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/brocrobes/</guid>
      <description>Brocrobes is a browser extension that allows you to enrich any webpage with the your own, personalised help. When you click on the extension button, the extension will look for all text in the language you are learning on the page, and send that to the server. The server will then get context-based definitions for all the words, and translations for all the sentences, and send that back to the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/home/</guid>
      <description>See here for more details on the scientific theories behind the Transcrobes project.
Understanding language learning You can find detailed getting started information for beginners, or for advanced Beginners+. These pages give (quite long) introductions into many aspects of language learning that you might not think of but are important if you want to learn efficiently, so when you have some spare time, you should take a few moments to read through them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moocrobes</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/moocrobes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/moocrobes/</guid>
      <description>Authentic video, particularly supported by subtitles, can be a highly effective language learning tool. Normal players, however, are not optimised for language learning, and subtitles are either in the language of the video or the native language of the viewer. Also, very few platforms enrich subtitles with hypertext features (clickable definitions, etc.) and no other platforms gloss only the words that the learner doesn&amp;rsquo;t know.
You can access the video content from the Contents menu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notrobes</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/notrobes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/notrobes/</guid>
      <description>Notrobes allows you to search for words (individual characters that are not words and radicals coming soon), and gives you significant amounts of information about those words, including your interaction with them.
Using Notrobes Simply enter a word in the language you are learning into the word entry textbox and the system will go off and get tons of information about the word and the component parts of the word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repetrobes</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/repetrobes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/repetrobes/</guid>
      <description>Repetrobes is a digital flashcard (spaced repetition system), originally inspired by Anki, and also (currently) using a modified version of the SuperMemo 2 algorithm.
Work has started on a very significantly optimised, personalised, behaviour-based, AI-powered version, which will be integrated soon. This new version will take into account all the information the system has on you, not just your responses in the tool, making it a LOT more accurate and powerful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Textcrobes</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/textcrobes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/textcrobes/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you need to read text that is not in one of the other supported formats, like from a PDF or MS Word document. In these cases, as long as you can copy and paste the text, you can paste it into Textcrobes and get all the great tools and formatting options you have in the other reading tools.
You can also see your progress on the vocabulary (and soon grammar) contained in the video, and get some idea how difficult it might be for you now, and how that will change in the future if you continue your great work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard</title>
      <link>/page/software/learn/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/learn/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>The Dashboard gives you an entry point to all the application functions and a high level view of some progress indicators.
The &amp;ldquo;Goals Progress&amp;rdquo; widget gives a quick idea of how you are doing with all your Goals in one place.
Later on you will be able to personalise what information you put on the Dashboard but for the moment we are repeating the &amp;ldquo;Known Words and Characters&amp;rdquo; graph you can also find on the Stats page</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
