<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Transcrobes</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Transcrobes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In search of Science</title>
      <link>/post/in-search-of-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/in-search-of-science/</guid>
      <description>All models are wrong, but some are useful (after George E. P. Box)
 There seem to be two kinds of &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo;. One with a capital - Science - and one without - science. Alas, it appears that academics and commentators throughout the Western world are yet to discover this. We very predominantly hear them talk about &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo; with a lowercase &amp;ldquo;s&amp;rdquo; - at least in most types of popular and political discourse - when really they mean &amp;ldquo;Science&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to know a word, and how do we learn them?</title>
      <link>/post/knowing-a-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/knowing-a-word/</guid>
      <description>Probably the main indicator of progress in language learning is increasing &amp;ldquo;known vocabulary&amp;rdquo;. While that sounds pretty uncontroversial* and simple, actually deciding what &amp;ldquo;knowing a word&amp;rdquo; is is actually a subject of hot debate! Particularly when we need to be very precise about things - exactly what you need when you create software - things start to get much less clear.
How do you know whether you know something? The answer to this question is one that has challenged philosophers and sages since time immemorial!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning with Transcrobes</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started-beginner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/getting-started-beginner/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr  Do an (online or offline) introductory course to get started with learning grammar and basic vocabulary. Use the Transcrobes vocabulary learning and revision tools to super-charge your learning, and then use it to start consuming real content as soon as you feel you can.  Introduction Transcrobes already has a lot of advanced functionality, but here is some introductory advice on how to start using it for beginners to Chinese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started as an intermediate learner</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started-intermediate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/getting-started-intermediate/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Bootstrap  If you already use an application, then export the vocab you already know and import that as a list to Transcrobes. Importing let&amp;rsquo;s you bootstrap your account so the system learns what you know. If your current/previous application doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow that, or you are just getting started learning with software, then head to the Listrobes input tool and spend as much time as you can be bothered telling the system what words you already know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning using Transcrobes</title>
      <link>/post/learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/learning/</guid>
      <description>As a teenager (and later), you aren&amp;rsquo;t the &amp;ldquo;blank slate&amp;rdquo; that you are when you learn your first language. You have a certain number of skills and learning habits that need to be taken advantage of if you want to learn a language most efficiently. Transcrobes has already implemented a number of functionalities that help you better manage the activities that are most valuable and useful for learning. Development of features is driven by science - unfortunately something that is often lacking in both mandatory schooling and software designed for language learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Server Experiment</title>
      <link>/post/experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/experiment/</guid>
      <description>After many months of intense focus on developing new features and making the system faster and more scalable, the system is now ready for real learners, adding real value for language learners who wish to super-charge their learning in a fun and efficient way.
Experimental platform The Meaningful IO research project experimental server is now live, and accepting signups for learners of Mandarin Chinese who are willing to participate in the research project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering L2</title>
      <link>/post/engineering-l2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/engineering-l2/</guid>
      <description>This post is in a series of posts discussing issues of a &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; theory of SLA - Meaningful IO.
Theorising vs Doing One of the things that you learn &amp;ldquo;down in the trenches&amp;rdquo;, doing actual software engineering on real world problems, is that theories about the world almost always can&amp;rsquo;t just be implemented as-is in software and solve a problem in an optimal way. Theorising of any kind necessarily needs to to abstract away some of the details and will focus on a particular aspect or set of aspects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anton&#39;s PhD thesis</title>
      <link>/post/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/phd/</guid>
      <description>I (Anton) have been accepted to develop the ideas in this project for a PhD thesis at the Linguistics and Translation department of the City University of Hong Kong from September 2019. While it is not certain that this particular code-base will be developed for the PhD, the PhD work will be open source, and there is no particular reason for it not to build on the existing code.
This means I will be working on this (or an equivalent) project for the next four years!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English support</title>
      <link>/post/english-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/english-support/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: 2020-12-01 English support has been temporarily removed in order to focus fully on Chinese. If there is significant community interest, that could always change.
Preliminary support for Chinese learners of English has been implemented and is now available for testing. As expected, integrating a second language pair required basically rewriting the entire system to be able to handle any input and output language.
That said, the inflectional characteristics of English are a new challenge for the system and have not been fully integrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Kubernetes</title>
      <link>/post/migrating-to-kube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/migrating-to-kube/</guid>
      <description>This is Part 3 of a mini-series of my experiences getting Transcrobes migrated from separate server apps on a 4gig Alibaba Cloud VM to microk8s on the same VM, and automating (almost) everything with Gitlab CI.
Check out Part 1 here and Part 2 here.
Kubernetes Migration Woes nginx-ingress I was coming from a setup where I knew the component parts (Apache + mod_wsgi) pretty well. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been working on high-load web stuff for over 8 years now, and always thought that nginx was a lot of hype for not much benefit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-User Production on Microk8s</title>
      <link>/post/single-user-prod-microk8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/single-user-prod-microk8s/</guid>
      <description>This is Part 1 of a mini-series of my experiences getting Transcrobes migrated from separate server apps on a 4gig Alibaba Cloud VM to microk8s on the same VM, and automating (almost) everything with Gitlab CI.
Introduction Microk8s is a kube-in-a-box distribution sponsored by Ubuntu, and in this blog post I recount my experiences getting my own personal Transcrobes installation migrated to a Kubernetes Helm chart and running on it on a 4GB VM on Alibaba Cloud in China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-26-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/2018-11-26-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This blog post announces the official open-sourcing of the (brand new) Transcrobes project. Code is available for all components on Gitlab.
Some ideas were originally posted to Blogger before the code was open-sourced. Future blogposts on the project by the maintainers should happen directly on https://transcrob.es.
Transcrobes proposes a new paradigm for language learning, one that finally puts each individual language learner at the centre of everything. Content-based instruction, extensive reading and other modern approaches have been pushing in this direction for several decades, Transcrobes is an open source project that takes this approach to the logical conclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Language Conspiracy</title>
      <link>/post/superpowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/post/superpowers/</guid>
      <description>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reification_(fallacy) Reification is part of normal usage of natural language (just like metonymy for instance), as well as of literature, where a reified abstraction is intended as a figure of speech, and actually understood as such. But the use of reification in logical reasoning or rhetoric is misleading and usually regarded as a fallacy. According to Alfred North Whitehead, one commits the fallacy of misplaced concreteness when one mistakes an abstract belief, opinion, or concept about the way things are for a physical or &amp;ldquo;concrete&amp;rdquo; reality: &amp;ldquo;There is an error; but it is merely the accidental error of mistaking the abstract for the concrete.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
