<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Configure on Transcrobes</title>
    <link>/page/software/configure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Configure on Transcrobes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</webMaster><atom:link href="/page/software/configure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/home/</guid>
      <description>Common data and configuration tasks Name Task Type Status Comments reader settings Reader config available Personlise the reading aids imports Data/Content import available Supported formats: TXT, CSV, epub (v3), SRT, VTT (more soon) user dictionaries Dictionary management available Override system defaults with personalised meaning/translation providers vocabulary bootstrap Known vocabulary input available Quickly teach the system what you know exports Data export available Word-level and daily activity exports (more soon) word lists Define meaningful vocabulary/grammar sets Vocabulary available Grammar lists available soon goals Define personal goals Basic availability Goals based on single lists and basic progress information available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contents</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/contents/</guid>
      <description>Contents are created by first importing a supported file format, and then telling the system to enrich them. After enriching you can use boocrobes to read ebooks and moocrobes to watch videos.
Enriching is a complex process that makes sure all of the content has been properly analysed and that you have all the data you need to get maximum value, including all the glosses, parts of speech and soon grammar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enrichment</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/enrichment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/enrichment/</guid>
      <description>A primary goal of the system is to &amp;ldquo;increase the bandwidth to the brain&amp;rdquo; - giving you exactly the extra information you need to be able to understand and also to learn most efficiently.
Tip
The page has information on how the system works under the hood. It is not required if you just want to use the system.
The system is able to give detailed, personalised help for each word (and soon grammatical patterns too) because of two things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exporting user data</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/exports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/exports/</guid>
      <description>You can currently export all the data that the system records and processes about your activity on the platform. These are exported in CSV format, and could be used in a spreadsheet app like Google Sheets or Microsoft Excel for making more complicated graphs than we provide today. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to send us your suggestions if you think you have a graph that others might like, so we can implement it directly on the platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossing types</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/glossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/glossing/</guid>
      <description>You can configure these options wherever that makes sense on the content screens.
Because all learners have different language backgrounds, glossing with another language may not be the best way for you to understand and learn, so a few other options are currently provided. This is one of the active research aspects of the platform - what are the best glossing techniques for learners, if they have a choice between several?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/goals/</guid>
      <description>One of the key philosophical drivers behind Transcrobes is learner freedom. Traditional approaches typically have a very rigid idea about what every learner is like and what they should learn, and they don&amp;rsquo;t particularly care that learners are actually people, rather than &amp;ldquo;scientific abstractions&amp;rdquo; or customers. Transcrobes puts each individual learner in the driver&amp;rsquo;s seat. The learner knows what their macro-level goals are, and Transcrobes is here to help the learner achieve those in a fun and highly efficient way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing lists and content</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/imports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/imports/</guid>
      <description>Discover how to use Imports on Supported formats Name Use case Details Supported Extensions CSV Word lists for monitoring exam progress or training the system on what you know Comma separated plain text files .csv TEXT Copy/paste from an unsupported format (like Word or PDF) Content files in plain text .txt SUBS Watch Chinese language video Find subtitles on sites like opensubtitles.org and import .srt, .vtt EBOOK Reading Chinese language books International standard format for eBooks .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listrobes</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/listrobes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/listrobes/</guid>
      <description>Discover how to use Listrobes on Listrobes is an input interface that allows you to indicate how well you know words very quickly. It can be used with or without the imports system to very quickly train the system, meaning onboarding can be very quick.
By default the system presents you with a list of the most common words, most common first, according to the University of Ghent &amp;ldquo;Open Subtitles ZH&amp;rdquo; (SUBTLEX-CH) list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preferences</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/preferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/preferences/</guid>
      <description>The preferences page allows you to configure the system with any system-wide preferences that aren&amp;rsquo;t directly related to a given tool (e.g, Repetrobes-specific preferences are configured directly in the tool).
Dark mode Dark mode is now fully supported. There is a known issue personalising text and gloss colour in boocrobes that is being worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader Settings</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/reader-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/reader-settings/</guid>
      <description>Each interface allows you to configure the reading aids (including for subtitles) in a fairly standard way, with some additions where that makes sense.
Each content screen has a button to take you to the specific configuration for it. Have a play and find what works for you best!
Main font configuration Here you can choose to override the default fonts in the interfaces where that makes sense, like boocrobes and moocrobes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Actions</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/system/</guid>
      <description>Warning
Whenever a new version is deployed you will need to first refresh the browser page (refresh button, F5, etc.) and then close the browser. Transcrobes makes heavy use of &amp;ldquo;service workers&amp;rdquo;, which need all browser tabs to be closed before taking effect. On Android, you may also need to clear the browser from memory, as Google is very aggressive in caching and this sometimes means it won&amp;rsquo;t perform the refresh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Dictionaries</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/userdictionaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/userdictionaries/</guid>
      <description>Personalised dictionaries may be imported and used with various parts of the system, including the comprehension aids (glosses, mouseovers, popups, etc.) and active learning tools (Repetrobes, etc.).
The system currently supports importing dictionaries in the CSV format with a fixed format. In-place editing of dictionaries will be made available at a later date.
Import options Column and field separators Import file structure The files imported MUST be in CSV format (and have a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word lists</title>
      <link>/page/software/configure/wordlists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>anton@transcrob.es (Anton Melser)</author>
      <guid>/page/software/configure/wordlists/</guid>
      <description>Discover how to use Wordlists on Wordlists are created by importing and analysing texts, then directing the system to create a list from the imported data. Texts can be simple lists of words (CSV or TXT are currently supported, more soon), or actual content (currently EPUB ebooks and SRT/VTT subtitles formats are supported, more soon). That makes it easy to both study lists like you might get for an exam, or a chapter in a textbook, but also content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
